JOSHUA OWENS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER ATLANTA, GA

PROFILE

p: (404) 906-8715 e: jko113@gmail.com http://www.joshuakowens.com/ https://www.github.com/jko113/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/jko113/

EDUCATION

- DigitalCrafts, immersive full-stack web development program (2018)
- Kennesaw State University, Graduate Certificate in Computer Science (2018)
- Indiana University, MA in Chinese (2013-2015)
- National Quemoy University, MBA (2010-2012)
- University of West Georgia, BA in Spanish and German (2007-2009)

SUMMARY

Building on 2+ years' experience in the tech industry and extensive training in software development, I aspire to produce quality software that improves people's lives. I am energized by working in a talented, dedicated team, and as a full-stack engineer experienced with various programming languages and in-demand technologies, I am equipped to offer valuable technical contributions to a wide range of software projects.

PROJECTS

- RepSearch (06/2018), an application to find out who your government officials are.
 Github: https://www.github.com/jko113/repsearch/
- Live site: http://www.github.com/jko113/repsearch/
- C0D3R (07/2018), a fun dating app for programmers.
 Github: https://www.github.com/jko113/c0d3r/
 Live site: http://www.c0d3r.joshuakowens.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

RouteMatch Software subject matter expert (08/2017-04/2018)

- act as tier 2 point of escalation for complex technical issues, writing custom code when applicable
- · own long-term projects for high-profile clients and keep internal and external stakeholders aware of progress
- collaborate with the development team on application bugs, feature enhancements, and product analysis
- train and coach junior members of the team on best practices, company technology, and stellar service

RouteMatch Software customer support specialist (12/2015-08/2017)

- · performed database management tasks, including restoring, updating, and maintaining databases
- provided technical consulting services to clients to maximize efficiency and improve data management
- · resolved a wide range of client-side technical issues using troubleshooting and problem-solving skills
- planned and executed short- and long-term projects, including upgrades and performance monitoring
- · interacted with diverse clientele and collaborated internally with various departments to enhance efficiency

The Carter Center China Program intern (09/2015-12/2015)

- provided frequent technical support on website maintenance, office and design software, and translation
- · recruited and managed a group of 6 volunteers at two international conferences

Lowe's Regional Distribution Center inventory specialist (03/2013-08/2013)

- · utilized Microsoft Access to design and use gueries of the facility's database information
- managed inventory software and conducted joint projects with various other departments in the warehouse
- · planned and executed technical management of product placement, storage, and flow in the warehouse